## RYAN BURNETT

Chicago, IL 60618 | Phone: 773-673-3982 | Email: ryanpburnett@yahoo.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ryan-burnett-912b8667

Github: <a href="https://github.com/ryanpburnett">https://github.com/ryanpburnett</a> | Portfolio: <a href="https://ryanpburnett.github.io/">https://ryanpburnett.github.io/</a>

#### SUMMARY

Full-stack web developer leveraging experience as an educator, composer and musician to create a creative, clean, and useful web experience for the end user. Previous experience in teaching with an ability to learn quickly and find creative solutions to problems.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL, Java

**Technologies:** jQuery, Node, Express, React, Angular, MongoDB

### **PROJECTS**

Let's Go! | https://github.com/ryanpburnett/Project-3 | https://glacial-waters-54685.herokuapp.com

- This app will allow the user to be able to explore whichever city they're in on a bike, and find points of interest and rest stops along the way.
- Role Played: back end coding team, specifically working on GeoJSON and getting locations to render. I also helped with designing React components.
- Technologies Used: React, Leaflet, GeoJason, and MongoDB, and is deployed with Heroku.

LyricLysteners | https://github.com/ryanpburnett/lyric-finder | https://ryanpburnett.github.io/lyric-finder

- A lyric finder site that generates lyrics for any song, along with a QR code linking to related YouTube videos.
- Role Played: back end coding team, specifically implemented the QR codes generated for the site.
- This app uses the <u>HappiDev API</u> and the <u>QR code generator API</u>.

Chord Progression Generator | <a href="https://github.com/ryanpburnett/chord-progression">https://github.io/chord-progression</a> | <a href="https://github.io/chord-progression/index.html">https://github.io/chord-progression</a> | <a href="https://github.io/chord-progression/index.html">https://github.io/chord-progression</a> | <a href="https://github.io/chord-progression/index.html">https://github.io/chord-progression</a> | <a href="https://github.io/chord-progression/index.html">https://github.io/chord-progression/index.html</a> | <a href="https://github.io/chord-progression/index.html">https://github.io/ch

- A fun project I've been working on! This site generates chord progressions, 12-tone rows, and single row rhythm matrices. Future iterations of this project will feature a play button with dynamically generated MIDI sound.
- Sole Developer; app is written in vanilla JavaScript.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Full stack developer Infosys

2021 – Present Remote / Lisle, IL

Full stack developer on bench, developing skills in Java, Angular, and Spring Boot.

## PK-8 general music teacher/choir director Pope Francis Global Academy

2018 - 2021

Chicago, IL

Elementary Music teacher responsible for teaching general music, directing the school choir, and leading the after school guitar program. Communication is a key transferable skill from this role, as it was necessary for teaching a wide range of ages and skill levels, as well as being able to collaborate well with parents, other teachers, and administration. Being able to think well on my feet is another key skill transferable from this role, as lesson plans frequently need to be adjusted on the fly to accommodate student learning.

## Key Accomplishments:

Founded the school choir

- Founded the after school guitar program
- Designed and directed assemblies throughout school year
- Collaborated with other teachers in designing and teaching cross-disciplinary classes
- Engaged in professional development, focusing on classroom management and curriculum development

## K-8 general music teacher/ Alfred Nobel Elementary School

2015 – 2018 Chicago, IL

Similar job description and responsibilities as above.

- Co-founded after school band
- Designed and directed assemblies throughout school year
- Directed music for graduation ceremony
- Coordinated and chaperoned field trips

## **EDUCATION**

**Full Stack Web Development Certificate:** Northwestern University - Evanston, IL A 6 month intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

## Master's Degree in Music Education - Illinois PEL:

VanderCook College of Music - Chicago, IL

## **Bachelor's Degree in Music Performance:**

Northeastern Illinois University - Chicago, IL